原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
翻译     学术男优  小酸奶
翻译     克里斯  子V
翻译     苏葵  Eunice
校对     克里斯
时间轴     西·查  想念Gallifrey的wholock
后期     8T
总监     somehacker  克里斯
天鹅绒圆锯
巴塞尔艺术展
迈阿密海滩
明显是弄错了
There's obviously a mistake.
有人通知我们各自的票已经准备好了
We were notified the passes would be waiting in our names.
抱歉  但不是那样的
I'm sorry, but that's incorrect.
-莫弗·范德瓦尔特  艺术网站  -不  是今天
- Morf Vandewalt, Artweb. - No. It's today...
你好  莫弗
Hey, Morf.
我要和这里的负责人谈谈
Okay, I wanna speak to someone in charge, please.
-很高兴再次见到你  -简直荒谬
- Lovely to see you again. - This is ridiculous.
我们上个月在纽约买了舒格伦的「超世界」
We bought Shogrun's Ultraworld last month in New York.
我的房子里不存在混乱
萨德勒系列
我愿意为了食物去工作
流浪侠
你感受过被忽视吗
Have you ever felt invisible?
我曾经建过铁路
Once, I built a railroad.
-你在这啊  莫弗  -克劳迪欧
- There he is. Morf. - Cloudio.
你估计知道了  这是建治的作品  叫「流浪侠」
It's Kenji, you probably know. It's titled Hoboman.
反响非同一般
The response is amazing.
可以说  是整个艺术展的亮点
Arguably, the hit of the show.
沃夫森的「女性雕塑」  四年前的老把戏
Wolfson, Female Figure, four years ago.
不  这是全新的  截然不同的主题
No, it's new. Vastly different themes.
新瓶装旧酒罢了
It's an iteration.
毫无原创  没有勇气  我这样认为
No originality. No courage. My opinion.
我绝对尊重你个人观点的权威
Well, I absolutely respect the power of your point of view,
但这个作品涵盖全球
but this encompasses on a global scale.
当下感夺人眼球
There's just such a sense of now and in your face,
表达了流行音乐  电影和经济
which speaks to pop and cinema and economics.
你可以感受到一股末日之风
I mean, you can feel the winds of the apocalypse.
我救不了你
I can't save you.
有人愿意用400万美元买下  是上海的大买家
We have a four-million-dollar hold, a major buyer in Shanghai.
你今天会发表评论吗
Will you be running your review today?
可可
你有空吗
Do you have a minute?
没有  我要进去了
No, I'm just heading inside now.
-我要告诉你一件有关瑞奇的事  -怎么了
- I have to tell you something about Ricky. - What?
-约瑟芬娜  他出轨了  -你认真的吗
- Josephina, he's cheating on you. - Are you serious?
-我看见他和一个女孩在一起  -什么时候
- I saw him with this girl. - When?
昨晚在一个酒吧
Last night at a bar.
-什么  -他们都喝得很醉
- What? - They were both pretty drunk.
-几点钟  -不清楚  大约十点
- Wha... What time? - I don't know. Ten?
-他们打得火热  -就在酒吧里
- They were all over each other. - Right at the fucking bar.
-真遗憾  约瑟芬娜  -你确定是他吗
- I'm so sorry, Josephina. - Are you sure it was him?
他们就站在我旁边
They were standing right next to me.
我得挂了
I gotta go.
-有什么我能做的吗  -没有
- Anything I can do? - No.
谢了  真的  再见
Uh, thank you, seriously. Bye.
-还好吗  莫弗  -你好  乔恩
- Howzit, Morf? - Hello, Jon.
很了不起  是吧
Really something, eh?
皮尔斯和桃乐西有一腿吗
Is Piers sleeping with Dorothy?
那你得问他本人了
Oh, I'm certain you'd have to ask him that.
失陪
Excuse me.
-莫弗  亲爱的  -格雷琴
- Morf, love. - Oh, Gretchen.
我们为博物馆竞标下了这幅画
We bid on it for the museum.
乔恩想出370万买下
Jon wants three point seven.
洛多拉绝不会低于500万卖皮尔斯的作品
Rhodora would never sell a Piers for under five,
所以这对我们来说是个好机会
so it's a nice opportunity for us.
我很好奇你是怎么想的
I'm quite curious to know what you think.
我觉得戒酒对他不利
I think sober hasn't been good for him.
这是他在15年前完成的
Well, this was done fifteen years ago.
正是皮尔斯当时酗酒最严重的时候
Piers was in the full bloom of alcoholism here.
没错
Exactly.
所以你觉得这对博物馆来说挺划算
So, you're saying it is a good buy for the museum, then?
失陪
Excuse me.
约瑟芬娜
Josephina.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
绝对是最糟糕的一天了
Literally, the worst fucking day.
你的妆都花了
Ugh, your makeup.
天呐  我迟到了
God, I'm late.
他们给我发了得有20次信息了
They texted, like, twenty times.
我也要去那儿
I'm headed there, too.
那些人真操蛋
God, fucking people.
-谁  -所有人
- Who? - Everyone.
皮尔斯要换画廊了吗
Is Piers switching galleries?
我就负责接电话和买咖啡
I answer phones and get coffee.
就算是  我也会是最后知道的
I'd literally be, like, the last to know.
你来太晚了  洛多拉已经拿到咖啡了
You're too late. Rhodora already got her coffee.
你在这个位置真的满意吗
Are you where you wanna be?
我才不要听安装工扯这一套
I'm not taking shit from the installer.
你觉得怎么样
What did you think?
我好多年都没这种感觉了
I haven't felt that in years.
-莫弗来了  -谢谢  失陪了
- Morf is here. - Oh, thank you. Excuse me.
怎么样
Well?
色彩  生命力
Color. Life.
我很喜欢
I love it.
我受够了空白的空间
I'm sick of white spaces.
太奇怪了
That is so strange.
就作品和颜料而言  最近我疯狂沉迷于
I've been drawn to a bolder booth presence in terms
更大胆的选择
of work and palette lately.
坚持使用空洞  单色的立方体来构图
This adherence to showing in sterile, monochrome cubes.
那只是偷懒罢了  我想把几种东西并列起来
It's just laziness. I wanted to get some juxtaposition going.
我其实正在写
I'm actually, I mean right now,
有关这方面的东西
writing something exactly about this.
这不在目录里面
This wasn't in the catalog.
这是明金斯的作品
It's Minkins.
叫做「球体」
It's called Sphere.
它能根据不同的人
It creates this unique sensation,
及他们决定去探索的洞
depending on each person
创造出独特的感受
and whatever hole they decide to explore.
就和生活一样
Just like life.
它使用了各种传感器和小装置
It uses all sorts of sensors and gizmos.
它是关于选择  欲望  性
It's about choice, desire, sex.
一应俱全
The whole enchilada.
-这是突破性的  -由你来让它突破
- It's groundbreaking. - Hmm, it's yours to break.
十分钟前才首次亮相
Debuted ten minutes ago.
我要发一个评论  这个作品多少钱
I'm posting a review. How much is it?
谈钱比谈艺术容易多了
So much easier to talk about money than art.
有意思
Funny.
说起来  皮尔斯要离开你投靠乔恩·敦顿
Speaking of, is Piers leaving you for Jon Dondon?
我做皮尔斯代理人已经17年了
I've represented Piers for seventeen years.
你没回答我问题
That's not an answer.
你把手伸进去吧
Well, why don't you put your hand in?
看看有什么感觉
See what you feel.
-这不值得我去投资  -你错了
- It's just not worth my investment. - You're mistaken.
这将会是前所未有的体验
This is gonna be an uncommon event experience,
更不用说税收激励了
not to mention the tax incentive.
-迈阿密有水吗  -在酒吧那边  先生
- Is there water in Miami? - At the bar, sir.
-我不清楚  -操
- I don't know. - Fuck.
可以确保你得到联合主席的职位
I can guarantee your position as co-chair--
失陪  皮尔斯
Oh, excuse me. Piers.
在海洋中漂流着  而在绝妙的时刻
I was floating in the ocean, and, for this incredible moment,
我感受到自己的原始意识被激发了
it felt like I had tapped into a primal consciousness.
我与这个世界最存粹的形式相连
A connection to the world in its purest form.
瑞奇还不承认
Ricky's still denying it.
"求你了  宝贝  听我解释"
"Please, baby, let me explain."
我发誓  我想伤害他
I swear to God, I want to hurt him.
也许这能让你解脱去尝试新鲜的东西
Maybe it will free you up for new things.
我们的关系就是新鲜东西  他才搬进来
This was a new thing. He'd just moved in.
我不得不说
I have to say,
我对跟艾德的关系有了迟疑
I'm having my own major second thoughts about Ed.
他居然对我们结婚抱有幻想
He actually has some fantasy about us getting married.
我不会再跟艺术家约会了
I'm through dating artists.
他们已经在跟艺术谈恋爱了
They're already in a relationship.
听我说  达米什
Look, Damrish,
你的网站并没给人规模感和质感
your website doesn't give a sense of scale or texture.
但是亲眼在新艺术家博览会上看到你的作品
But seeing your work in person at the new-artists fair,
让我很是震惊
I had that "Oh, my God" moment.
它会控制你  向你攻击  吞噬你
It charges and mauls and devours.
六个月前  我流落街头
Six months ago, I was living on the street,
在人行道上展览
showing on the sidewalk.
我的背景就是这样的  对吧
So, that's where I'm coming from, right?
让我跟你说清楚
Let me fill you in.
所有这些
All this...
只是猎杀下一个新事物然后吃掉它
it's just a safari to hunt the next new thing and eat it.
我听说要对你格外小心
I heard you were the one to watch out for.
我是小菜一碟
I'm easy-peasy.
其实就是小猫
Pussycat, really.
我了解你的一切  之前那段朋克时光
I know all about you, going back to your punk days.
那可是很久之前的事了
Oof, that was many moons ago.
-天鹅绒圆锯乐队  -是的  名字很夺眼球
- Velvet Buzzsaw. - Yeah, well, the name was catchy.
早期的作品很棒
Yeah, the early stuff was great.
然后呢  变成自嘲的黑历史了
Then it became, what? Like, self-parody?
波莉离开后
I mean, after Polly left,
你们怎么就解散了
why'd you split up?
那时候酗酒嗑药那么多 谁还记得
Who remembers through all the booze and pills.
但重点是
But the point is,
我从无政府主义者变成了有品位的供应商
I've gone from anarchist to purveyor of good taste.
所以  我懂其中的把戏
So, I get the joke.
这都不新鲜  自从收取一块骨头来看壁画
None of this is new. It's all been done since
就有人这么干了
someone charged a bone to see the first cave painting.
给
Here you are.
所以  谢谢你
So... Thank you.
你在哪个画廊展览
What cave are you showing in?
我和我的兄弟们搞了个系列
Me and my dudes started a collective.
为它干杯
Well, cheers to that.
谁都知道我喜欢忠诚
Well, hell knows, I love loyalty,
但我巴不得展出你的作品
but I would kill to exhibit you.
我刚拒绝乔恩·敦顿给我办个人作品展
I just turned down an offer for a full show from Jon Dondon.
真是没完没了
And on and on.
他正在里面想把皮尔斯挖过去
He's inside right now trying to poach Piers.
你知道我在哪吗  达米什
You know where I am, Damrish?
我在这儿和你一起喝酒
I'm here doing shots with you.
苏打汽水加青柠
Club soda. Lime.
整个市场一直都对你翘首以盼  皮尔斯
The market always tiers up for you, Piers.
听我说  我已经受不了你这些屁话
Listen, my intolerance for your bullshit is zero.
好的  不说屁话
Lekker, no bullshit.
洛多拉给你报价过高
Look, Rhodora overpriced you.
她失去理智了  完全不了解最新的情况
She's lost it. She's completely out of touch.
我今天以370万的价格卖出了「颅骨」
I sold Cranial today for three point seven,
和我预期的一样
exactly what I said I'd get.
如果你加入我  我们画廊有最顶尖的分析技术
If you come with me, our gallery has cutting-edge analytics
可以最大化交易流和全球需求
to maximize deal flow and global demand.
我正在努力重新创作  去启发
I am fighting to get back to creation, to revelation,
我们大脑中闪烁了数十亿年的能量
the billion years of energy sparking through our brain.
我才不会满世界乱跑去卖展览的门票
I'm not jetting around, hawking fucking tickets.
在注意力经济中  名人就是艺术形式的一种
In an attention economy, celebrity is art form.
你知道我只委托新的作品吗
Do you understand that I only commission new work?
复刻  印刷和仿制品都是以我自己的品牌销售
Repros, prints, replicas are all marketed under my own brand.
老兄  能与你在未来的作品上
My boet, I'm more than ecstatic
进行合作  我非常高兴
to partner you exclusively on your future work.
我听说洛多拉把「球体」卖了700万美元
I hear Rhodora sold Sphere for seven million.
老天  那作品不过是个嘉年华
Man, it's a carnival attraction.
那作品很棒
It's brilliant.
我不该戒酒的
I never should've quit drinking.
约瑟芬娜
Josephina.
你要去SLS吗
Are you going to SLS?
我要去城外的一个小展览
I'm going to a satellite show outside of town.
我也去
Well, I'll come.
你怎么了
What's going on with you?
你什么意思
What do you mean?
你他妈可是莫弗·范德瓦尔特
You're Morf fucking Vandewalt.
你和我去一个资助的展览做什么
What are you doing coming to a grant show with me?
我喜欢和你在一起
I like being with you.
我们品味相投
We have a taste relationship.
你抽的是烟吗
Is that tobacco?
大麻油
Hash oil.
要不我也来一小口
Maybe I'll have one little puff.
那是我这几年来看过最差的展览
Okay, that was the worst show I've seen in years.
我们走的时候那个发火的人是谁
And who was that angry guy when we left?
你不认识
You don't know?
那是伊梅尔德斯·范德霍斯特  你去年抨击过他
That was Imeldus Vanderhorst. You panned him last year.
从冰箱里拿两瓶酒出来
Grab two Tito's from the fridge.
你的身材比瑞奇的好多了
You know, you're in much better shape than Ricky.
我经常做普拉提和骑自行车
I... do a lot of Pilates and Peloton.
我记得你的身体
I remember your body.
我也记得你的
I remember yours.
自打柏林之后  我一直都在想你
Ever since Berlin, I find myself thinking all the time about you.
我们当时都醉了
We were wasted.
我也一直这样告诉自己
I keep telling myself that.
你的皮肤
Your skin.
是杏仁色和马鞍棕之间最美丽的融合
It's the most beautiful cross between almond and saddle brown.
我让你硬了吗
I make you hard, huh?
你让我困惑了
You make me confused.
这对一个评论家来说太难了
Tough headspace for a critic.
昨天很晚回到洛杉矶  看了下数据
Got back to LA late last night and looked at the numbers.
我的天
My God.
除了明金斯的作品卖了个好价
Aside from the peachy Minkins sale,
迈阿密不是一个非常繁荣的市场
Miami was really not a very great thriving market.
实际上  鲁贝克的作品一件都没卖出去
Brass tacks, we didn't move one Rubek.
我知道伦敦办事处很想把他挖过去
I know the London office has a hard-on for him,
但在我看来
but to my mind,
他们最不应该把时间浪费在
the last thing we need to waste time
出售复兴的流行艺术品上
on is trying to flog some pop-art revival.
流行艺术
Pop-art.
我操
Fuck me.
天鹅绒圆锯
"明日新星区域获奖作品是
"Star of the Nova section was
玛蒂尔达·斯普拉德的Go-Pro幼儿园
Mertilla Splude's Go-Pro Kindergarten,
对孩童时期经历的卓越展现  颇受启发"
an inspired disquisition of early-age experience."
赶紧启发自己和我一起跳进泳池吧
Well, get inspired and come join me in the pool.
他没事吧
Is he all right?
叫救护车
Call 911.
谁该坐在这里的
Who's supposed to be here?
约瑟芬娜  她...又迟到了
Josephina. She's late... again.
洛可可  你去前台
You, Rococo. Take the reception desk.
其实我叫可可
It's... It's Coco, actually.
迷雾画廊  请问有什么需要
Haze Gallery. Can I help you?
喂
Hello?
已经挂了吧  对  有钱人就没什么耐心
Hang up, right? Yeah, rich people are impatient.
我其实也算是个艺术家
I'm really an artist, you know?
我画了《班迪尼水果圈河马》  知道吗
I did, um, Bandini's Froot Loop Hippo, you know that?
然后我贴在所有水果圈麦片上
And I glued on all the Froot Loops.
嗯
Yeah.
现在放在布罗德博物馆呢
It's at The Broad right now.
不是布洛德  人们总是搞混
Not broad. People confuse it with Broad.
-布罗德  布洛德  -好吧
- Broad, brode, yeah. - Right.
但是如果你想去看  我可以搞到票
But I can get us tickets if you want.
那边的人认识我
They know me there.
-你什么时候回来的  -昨晚
- When did you get back? - Last night.
我有可靠消息称皮尔斯离开你转投乔恩·敦顿了
I have solid confirmation Piers has left you for Jon Dondon.
我都快感到无聊了
I'm going to get bored now.
我倒觉得这很严重  他为什么离开
This feels huge to me. Why would he leave?
没有死亡
没有艺术
为什么  为什么  什么为什么
Why, why why. Why anything?
也许我希望他离开
Maybe I wanted him to leave.
同时我还签了新的艺术家
Meanwhile, I'm signing new talent.
听说你签了达米什  他很厉害
Heard you got Damrish. He's fierce.
今天早上还签了玛蒂尔达·斯普拉德
And this morning, Mertilla Splude.
我发誓  我们俩真是太搭了
We are on the same frequency, I swear.
Go-Pro幼儿园绝对会轰动
Go-Pro Kindergarten's gonna break big.
你简直就是上帝的枕边人
Your lips, God's ear.
等等  在我们的世界中  你就是神
Oh, wait. In our world, you are God.
我要迟到了  先挂了
And I'm running late. Gotta go.
好的
Okay.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我们楼里突然死了个人
Some random guy just, like, died in my building.
我真是太惊讶了
I really am so surprised.
洛多拉  我没和你开玩笑
Rhodora, I'm not kidding.
我的一个邻居真的死了  是我发现尸体的
A neighbor actually died. I found the body.
布莱森随时向我汇报
Bryson keeps me up to speed on everything
这里发生的事
that goes on around here.
包括你经常迟到
Your chronic lateness--
布莱森不爽是因为
Bryson's pissed because...
他追求过我  我拒绝了
he came on to me and I shut him down.
他就是个混蛋
He's a flat-out creeper.
我只能说  曾经我对你抱有的兴趣已经消磨光了
Well, I can say the interest I had in you has waned.
我原以为能好好培养你
I thought I was grooming a protégé.
我们曾经就你的挣扎和远大理想进行过无数次长谈
All our long talks about your struggles and grand ambitions.
而你却侮辱了我的智商
And then you insult my intelligent mind.
我要把你从前台撤下来了
I'm moving you off the front.
不准再接触客户
No client contact
等你好好提升自己的艺术标准吧
until you raise the quality bar in your performance.
-早上好  -早上好
- Morning. - Good morning.
柏林  新加坡  伦敦的都上线了吗  看到了
Do we have Berlin? Singapore? London? Oh, we do.
我最近看上了两名新的艺术家
So, I have two new favorite artists
我想向你们好好介绍一下
I am all kinds of happy to tell you about.
我是佩拉克公司的
I'm from Perlack.
维特利尔·迪斯
这幢楼是我们的
We own the building.
你认识他吗
Did you know him?
死掉的那个人
The guy who died?
好像是什么艺术家
Some sorta artist, I guess.
不认识
No.
是我找到他的尸体的
I found his body.
他很注重自己的隐私
He liked his privacy.
-他有一只猫  -还在里面  我们明天找
- He had a cat. - It's up there. We'll find it tomorrow.
天啊  房间里的东西...
Jesus, the stuff inside...
都要扔了
And it all gets tossed.
那老家伙本来希望把所有东西都扔了
The old man wanted everything thrown away.
他吩咐的  不留任何痕迹
No trace, his instructions.
看来他都开始自己动手扔了
Looks like he started to do it himself,
可惜还没扔完  自己就死了
but he died before he could finish the job.
晚安
Well, good night.
猫咪  猫咪
Hey, kitty, kitty.
小家伙
Hey, little guy.
你打来真是太好了
So glad you called.
我也想抱你  但我浑身是汗
I'd hug, but I'm all sweaty.
这件针织衫真不错  玉米色很衬你
Love the jumper. Cornsilk's a great color for you.
迈阿密堪称天启
Miami was a revelation.
我就这么说吧
Let me just start with that.
我不知道我的生命中还有其他
I don't know where I am with anything else in my life,
能比我和你一起时...
other than that I feel...
感觉更好
good with you.
好多了  超乎寻常
So much better, and beyond good.
我发现了一点东西
I found something.
我就是这个意思
That's what I'm saying.
这是谁画的
Who did these?
你觉得这些画怎么样
What do you think of them?
颇有远见
They're visionary.
令人痴迷  非常令人震惊的...
Mesmeric. An absolute incredible...
素材结合
mix of mediums.
我完全倾倒了
I'm ensorcelled.
-你觉得这些画有市场吗  -大市场
- Do you think there's a market for it? - Massive.
超大
Beyond.
谁代理的
Who represents them?
我
I do.
我的好奇心快溢出来了
I'm dying with suspense.
是谁
Who is it?
今晚的大奖为四亿
Tonight's jackpot is 400 million dollars.
要赢得大奖  必须五个白球上的号码全中
To win that jackpot, you must match these five white balls.
第一个号码是54   接下来是32
The first winning number tonight is 54. That's followed by 32.
接下来是52  下一个是34
Up next we have 52. Your next number is 34.
本周五晚最后一个白球上的号码是25
Your final white ball for this Friday evening is 25.
如果没有人的号码全中
If no one matches the five numbers--
双年展时好像看起来很前卫一点
It just seemed edgier at the Biennale.
用的就是当初的灯光吗
Oh, is this the exact lighting?
应该是的
I think so.
你去核实一下规格
Okay, well, go check the specs.
我负责达米什那个系列的
I run the collective Damrish belongs to.
我不知道系列还有专门的负责人
I didn't think collectives had people in charge.
那不是就和系列的初衷不符了吗
Doesn't that defeat the whole purpose?
我代理他的
I represent him.
曾经代理
Used to.
我们要创造跟这些商业垃圾完全不一样的东西
We're building something away from all this commercial bullshit.
这不仅仅为了什么钱
It's not just about the fucking money.
你夺走达米什会毁了我们
Stealing Damrish away would end us.
你知道吗  他已经不是小孩子了
Okay. Well, you know what? He's not a child.
这是他的选择  不是我的
It's his choice, not mine.
-你觉得这就完了吗  -给我后退
- You think this is done? - Back the fuck up!
我想阻止他的来着
I tried to stop him.
你失败了
Okay, well, you failed.
难以置信
Unbelievable.
-以后不会...再发生这种事了  -出去
- It will... never happen again. -Go!
可可  你不是和我说过你想要一只猫吗
Coco! Didn't you tell me you wanted to get a cat?
我们能等会再聊吗
Can we talk about it later?
好的
Sure.
你以为你在干什么
What the fuck do you think you're doing?
这是什么  这是谁画的
What is this? Who is this?
这是放在我桌子下的
That was under my desk.
我在找胶带  然后就看到了
I was looking for tape and I saw this.
-你这是骚扰  -告诉我这个艺术家是谁
- This is harassment. - Tell me who the artist is.
你到底什么毛病
What the fuck is wrong with you?
我不仅仅只是个维修和打包的人
I do more than maintenance and packing.
我不是个单单四肢发达的家伙
I'm not just a man of primitive skills.
这东西...和我有共鸣
This shit... talks to me.
你好啊  我听说了你要来
Hey, you. I heard you were coming by.
我在评估你的珀尔福展览
I'm reviewing your Purlfoy exhibit.
行行好  我们人手越来越少了
Be kind. Our membership is plummeting.
告诉我
Tell me something.
你有没有听说过一个叫维特利尔·迪斯的艺术家
Have you ever heard of an artist named Vetril Dease?
-迪斯  -没听说过
- D-e-a-s-e. - No.
你能查一下吗
Can you check?
我们的记录中没有  我们可是记录了所有人
No. Not in our records, and we have everyone.
莫弗  亲爱的  我
Morf, honey, I, uh...
我要和你说一件事
I need to bend your ear.
我要离开这里  去当艺术顾问了
I am leaving to become an art adviser.
我知道  我知道  我不能说是为谁
I know, I know. I can't say for whom.
但是我赚的钱
But I will be making enough
足够买一辆超棒的车和一个花园了
to afford a terribly lovely car and garden.
你好  莫弗
Oh, hello, Morf.
你好  吉姆
Hello, Jim.
我当初来艺术馆
Look, I came to the museum
就是为了想通过艺术改变世界
because I wanted to change the world through art.
但是财富吞噬了一切  只剩下一些碎屑
But the wealthy vacuum up everything, except crumbs.
只有少数人才能欣赏优秀的作品
The best work is only enjoyed by a tiny few.
那些人听人说该买什么就买什么  何不加入他们呢
And they buy what they're told. So, why not join the party?
什么事都离不开钱
It's everywhere, the money question.
为了做好铺垫  我正在
In advance of my move, I am...
积极地为我的新客户寻找艺术品
actively looking for purchases for my new client.
你说不定会感兴趣
You might be interested to know
我可以给你提供一大笔
that I can provide to you a generous,
无法追迹的钱
untraceable reward for anything
只要你给我提供一些
you steer me to in the realm of
定价过低或是提前评估的作品
undervalued, pre-review, perhaps.
我不做这种生意
I don't do that.
那你和洛多拉的协议呢
What's your arrangement with Rhodora?
没有协议
None.
那她总是在你给出好评价之前买下作品
Then her buys prior to your favorable reviews
都只是有先见之明吗
are utterly prescient?
我的人生就是这样
This is my life.
我能和作品有一些精神上的联系
How I connect with some sort of spirituality at actual present.
当然了
Of course.
我的评价是出于我的欣赏
I assess out of adoration.
我拓宽了我分析作品的领域
I further the realm I analyze.
原谅我  我...
Forgive me, I...
操
Fuck.
亲亲
Kisses.
怎么了
What's going on?
你说呢
You tell me.
你来这里干什么
What are you doing here?
上帝啊
Hell's bells.
布莱森
Bryson.
-了不起  -我要请你离开了
- Incredible. - I'm going to have to ask you to leave.
除非你用枪指着我
Not if you had a gun.
这不关你的事
It's none of your business.
其实还真有关系
Oh, actually it is.
你签署了竞业限制条款  如果你好好读了
You signed a non-compete clause, which, if you read,
你也许会记得
you might remember is
你要做的可远不止那些
very much quite a lot broader than that.
和我说说维特利尔·迪斯
Tell me all about Vetril Dease.
他的名字简直就是树上的金箔
His name is the tinsel on the tree.
别让我对你进行拷问了
Don't make me pull some sort of heavy interrogation.
现在  只有我和你
Right now, it's just you and me,
毕竟我们俩之间还有友谊和爱
with all our active friendship and love for each other.
你怎么得到这些画的
Now, how did you get all of these?
楼上的一个人  他死了
A guy upstairs. He died.
你就拿走了吗
And you just took them?
他没有家属和朋友
He had no family or friends.
我就不问那些显而易见的问题了
Well, I won't bother with the obvious questions,
不过  你肯定有一些大计划吧
but, oh, you must have some giant plans.
我是单干的行家
I invented do-it-yourself.
你绝对搞不定的  宝贝
And you're in way over your head, babe.
你必须归档  分类并确认所有权
You have to archive and catalog and establish ownership.
还要货币化
And monetize.
我愿意帮你做好这一切...只要合理分成
I'm willing to do all of that for... a reasonable percentage.
你可以跟我进行无尽的诉讼  或者
You can engage me in an endless lawsuit, or...
你可以变得有钱  出名并成功
you can become rich and famous and successful.
我们都知道这是你一直以来梦寐以求的
Which is what we both know you've always wanted.
我们可以说这些是被人遗弃的
We can claim the property was abandoned
前提是她说她是在垃圾桶里找到的
if she says she found it in the dumpster.
并着手寻找合适的主人
And took steps to find a rightful owner.
初步报道声称他没有继承人
Well, first reports are he had no heirs.
她只是个租客  大楼主人不能发个声明吗
She's just a tenant. Could the building owner make a claim?
那个处理的人说他们把所有东西都扔了
The salvage guy said that they were junking everything.
我花了好几个小时才把这些全搬到我的公寓
I mean, it took hours to carry it all down into my apartment.
实在是太多了
There was just so much of it.
不  你是在垃圾桶里找到画的  不是他的公寓
No, you found the art in the trash, not in his apartment.
这是很重要的
This is very important.
回想一下  你是在垃圾桶里找到的
Now, remembering back, you found it in the dumpster.
是那样的吗
Isn't that what happened?
垃圾桶
The dumpster.
没错  我记起来了
Yeah, I remember now.
艺术评论太过局限又耗费心神
Critique is so limiting and emotionally draining.
我一直想要表达一种长期的  超脱的观点
I've always wanted to do something long-form, beyond opinion.
将我的脚趾沉浸在对于原始和精华的探索中
Dip my toe into an exploration of origin and essence.
灵体到现实的转变
A metamorphosis of spirit into reality.
我一直没找到表达的载体  现在终于有了
I've... I've never had the vehicle until now.
一位艺术家在逆境中创作
An artist toiling in the recesses,
被发现死亡  我想立刻开始研究
discovered in death. I wanna start researching immediately.
有个时间的问题  要和我们庞大的市场布局吻合
Well, there's timing. Meshing with our extensive marketing plans,
我们还没进展到那部分
which we haven't gotten to yet.
我愿意写展览册
Well, I'm willing to write the exhibit brochure.
能立刻推动展览启动
That will give immediate weight to the launch.
相应地  我想独家拥有一本书
And in return, I want exclusive rights to a book
和一些画作
and several pieces.
听上去不错
Well, that sounds swell.
洛多拉
Hi, Rhodora.
我在归档他的材料
Well, I'm archiving his material,
然后对画作进行光谱解析
then running spectrums on his paint.
最奇怪的事情发生了
And it's the damnedest thing.
我都不知道怎么说明
I don't even know how to account for it.
让我不得不大胆猜测
I couldn't hazard a guess.
迷雾画廊  请稍等
Haze Gallery, please hold.
约瑟菲娜现在不方便接电话  但我能捎个信
Yes, Josephina's unavailable right now, but I can take a message.
好  请稍等
Okay, please hold.
迷雾画廊
Haze Gallery.
对  洛多拉知道开会的事
Uh, yes. Rhodora is aware of the meeting,
但她正在打电话
but she's on a call right now.
你确定是同一个人吗
You're positive it's the same Dease?
-对  -你怎么那么肯定
- Yeah. - Well, how can you be sure?
我去了精神病院  找到了他的病历
I visited the institution. I found his records.
-天啊  -换我不会担心
- Dear God. - I wouldn't worry.
这些文件太老了  没备份  我拿走了唯一一份
The file's so old, there's no backup. I took the only copy.
好吧  发过来  剩下的不用管了
Okay, send it over. And wash your hands of it.
-支票多加一个零  -谢了
- And add a zero to your bill. - Thanks.
维特利尔·迪斯最早出现于1930年洛城人口普查
Vetril Dease first appears in a 1930 Los Angeles census,
跟他的父亲  母亲
living in a low-income home
和妹妹住在一处低收入住房
with his father, mother and younger sister.
九年后  维特利尔和父亲成为了仅有的幸存者
Nine years later, Vetril is listed with his father
诡异大火烧死母亲和女儿
他们的房子被一场诡异的火灾吞噬
as the only survivors of a suspicious fire which swept their house.
大火之后不久  维特利尔出现在法庭文件中
Shortly after the fire, Vetril's named in a court document.
据记载  毫无人性的是
Citing cruelty beyond the bounds of humanity,
儿童保护组织将他从虐待狂父亲身边带走
child protection services remove Vetril from his abusive father
送去了位于南瓦莱乔的圣殿骑士孤儿院
and place him in the Good Templars Orphanage in South Vallejo.
那段时间的经历是个谜
His time there is a mystery,
唯一的记录就是他18岁时离开了
the only record being his departure at 18.
但真正的谜题是接下来发生的事
But the real mystery is what follows.
迪斯消失了三十年  人间蒸发
Dease disappears for three decades, vanishing like a ghost.
萨特勒退伍军人医院
他的名字突然重新出现在
He suddenly resurfaces on the payroll
萨特勒一处老兵机构的工资单上
of the Sawtelle veterans administration,
他在那里当门卫长达42年
where he was employed as a janitor for 42 years.
迪斯独居  与世隔绝
Dease lived alone and isolated,
用他的艺术深潜到他的精神世界
using his art to dive deep into his own psyche.
这位艺术家与自己的心魔抗争了几十年
The artist battled for decades with his personal demons.
以此换来了这暴力与疯狂的史诗
The result is an epic saga of violence and madness.
渴求答案的哀嚎  从未到来的解脱
A howl for answers and a resolution that never comes.
我前男友瑞奇周五有个展览
My ex-boyfriend, Ricky, has an exhibition Friday.
他是个蠢材
He's a hack.
满脸胡须  装腔作势
A bearded, downtown poser.
他这辈子连一个他自己的主意都没有
You know, he hasn't had, like, an original idea in his whole life.
除此之外  他剽窃别人的作品
On top of which, he steals from everyone.
但没关系
But you know that, right?
我非常熟悉他的作品
I'm very familiar with his work.
你应该去看他的展
You should go to his show,
亲眼看看他有多糟糕
see for yourself how much he sucks.
-然后做你该做的  -你认真的吗
- Then do what you do. - Are you serious?
为了我
For me.
你好  莫弗
Hello, Morf.
好吧
Right.
这是当代的吗
Is it contemporary?
它直奔主题  赋予了形式真正的情感
It cuts through the bullshit and gives form to true emotion.
-这想表达什么  -你感受到了什么
- What does it say? - What do you feel?
他们以全新的方式运用科技
They're using tech in a whole new way.
主旨在于建立一个包括所有媒介的平台
The idea is aiming for a platform that includes all media.
他不知从何而来  孑然一身
He came from nowhere, knew no one,
如果不是我们勤劳的约瑟芬娜善于观察
and if our industrious Josephina here hadn't been so observant,
他的杰作就可能被丢掉了
his genius work would've been thrown away.
他本可能会被遗忘的
And, um, he would've been consigned to oblivion.
借着路灯  我在一个垃圾堆旁发现的
I spotted it by a streetlight over a dumpster.
大约一共有多少作品
Approximately, how many pieces are there?
很不幸
Well, unfortunately,
迪斯先生可一点
Mr. Dease's output was the opposite from
也算不上多产
what one would call prolific.
他也肯定不会有新作品了
And he's certainly not making any more.
有一件我们很感兴趣
There's one we're very interested in.
顺便说一声  大家都抢破头了
Well, just know demand has people ready to kill.
真亮眼
Fetchin'.
在庄严的艺术面前  我忍不住颤抖
Before the sublime, the whole body quivers.
以这个价格  你们博物馆没戏了
Well, at these prices, your museum's locked out.
我昨天刚离开了  所以我能随便说了
Well, I just yesterday left the museum, so I can speak freely now.
-我现在是一位私人买家的顾问  -谁
- I'm an adviser for a private buyer. - Whom?
买了「球体」的那位
Our friend who bought Sphere.
你真幽默呀
Well, how hilarious for you.
以此为前提
In that capacity,
我确实为他挑中几件大幅画作
I do have my eye on several of the large-format product for him.
销售人员都忙得团团转
Well, the sales staff have been busy beavers.
所有作品都预定出去了
Everything's on reserve.
也许我们可以付定金
Perhaps we'd pay a premium.
-这也不能改变什么  -那什么有用
- That doesn't butter the biscuit. - Well, what the fuck would?
我卖给你两幅迪斯的
I'll sell you two Dease
前提是下个月达米什的首展你买三幅他的画
if you buy three pieces at Damrish's opening next month.
万一我的客户对达米什没感觉呢
What if my client doesn't respond to Damrish?
你是顾问  灌输给他
Well, you're the adviser. Advise.
不是吧
Damn.
下个月  轮你上场了
Next month, it's your show.
我得走了
I gotta-- I gotta go.
好的
Okay.
能看到有实质内容的作品真让人激动
Isn't it exhilarating to see something substantial?
不只是那些搞刺青的名人艺术家
I mean, other than celebrity tattoo artists and
拿气球当绘画工具  我在写关于他的书
balloons for painting tools. I'm writing a book about him.
我很讨厌你昨天发表的瑞奇·布莱恩的评论
I just loathed your Ricky Blane review yesterday.
我对他的展览很受启发
I thought his show was inspired.
可能我没看懂吧
Well, I didn't get it, I suppose.
我觉得我们看的完全是两个展
I felt that we saw totally different exhibits.
负面的评价总好过
A bad review is better than
消失在平庸之作中  不见天日
sinking into the great glut of anonymity.
-那是玩笑吗  -据我所知不是
- Was that a joke? - Not that I'm aware of.
瑞奇昨天喝醉了  出了车祸
Ricky got drunk and crashed his car last night.
他昏迷了
He's in coma.
我听说他都毁了
I heard he was crushed.
因为车祸吗
By the car?
你的评论  王八蛋
Your review. Arschloch.
你说什么  布莱森把部分画作搬去了仓库
What do you mean, Bryson's moving some of the art to storage?
如果钻石商一次发售所有钻石
Well, if De Beers released all their diamonds,
那它们就会变得一文不值
they'd be cheap as cut glass.
艺术学校没教过你这些吗
Didn't they teach any of this in art school?
我们要说他有多少作品
How many are we saying he made?
它们的价值恰恰在于稀少  所以那不是我们的说辞
Well, their value's their scarcity, so it's not what we say.
那是事实
It's the reality.
事实是楼上存了一千多幅
The reality is we have over one thousand pieces stored upstairs.
胡说
Well, that's nonsense.
我怀疑都不到五百
Why, I doubt if it's even half that number.
你做了什么
What have you done?
让它不参与流通
Removed them from circulation.
未雨绸缪
Locking them away for a rainy day.
操
Fuck.
操  操
Fuck! Fuck!
操
Fuck!
谦卑
该死  该死
shit. shit
该死
Oh shit.
有人吗
Hello?
你好啊  我是敦顿
Howzit? It's Dondon.
别激动  孩子  没到时候
- - Easy, boy. Not yet.
拜访工作室  我好激动
Studio visit. I'm excited.
我受不了乐天派
I can't stomach cheery or upbeat.
我不是傻子  记住了
I'm not an idiot. Remember that.
我很荣幸成为你的新经纪人
Hey, I'm honored to be your new representative
-看看你最近在忙什么  -我想也是
- and see what you've been up to. - I just bet you are.
奇迹发生的地方就是这里吗
So, this is where the magic happens?
这是个笑话吗
Is that a joke?
什么
Sorry?
这些是复制品
This is repros and replicas.
工作室在楼上
Studio's upstairs.
鲁珀特  上楼
Rupert, up.
太壮观了
This is remarkable.
那不是作品
It's not art.
怎么样
Well?
我...
Well, I...
我还在笑话  亲眼看见艺术的产生过程太激动了
I'm just soaking it in. It's thrilling to see a work in progress.
痛快点给我个看法  你眼前的画
Just give me an honest goddamn opinion about
到底怎么样
what you're looking at.
我能看出你作品的特征  所以...
I can see a line with your body of work. So...
我在抄袭自己
So, I'm copying myself?
如果是自己的作品  就不算抄袭
It's not copying if it's your canon.
我以为你的工作室在城里
I thought your studio was downtown.
太多诱惑了
Too many addiction triggers.
-我去年都在这工作  -我...
- I worked here the last year. - Well, I--
我很愿意看看你搬来之后的所有新作品
I'd love to see all the new work you've done since moving,
因为经纪团队都已经准备好
because the team is geared up and ready
卖出你的所有新作了
to sell every new piece you have.
好吧
Right.
当然了
Sure, of course.
不  你在构思
No, you've... you've been gestating.
构思预示着新生
Gestation implies birth.
灵感迸发  然而随即自我毁灭
Ideas come, but they kill themselves as soon as they appear.
这就是个屠宰场
This is a slaughterhouse.
欢迎入伙
Welcome aboard.
我们接到电话后  花了几天时间找到你们
When we got the call, it took us a few days to locate you.
我们一直很忙
We've been busy.
看起来他滑进了加油站的侧面
Now, it looks he slid into the side of a gas station
在加州国家森林公园外
out in Angeles National Forest.
这里已经关闭几年了
Place has been closed for years.
什么导致了车祸
What caused the crash?
不知道
Don't know.
也许他撞到头  就走偏了
Think he may have hit his head and wandered off.
这里很容易迷路
It's easy to get lost out there.
有什么发现吗
Was anything recovered?
都放在后面了
Well, we put it in the back here.
我们认为车子在被发现前可能遭到破坏
We think the vehicle may have been vandalized before we located it.
这附近有个很大的流浪汉聚集地
There's a big homeless camp near there.
他们如果先找到车子  很可能已经洗劫了
They would've cleaned it out if they found it first.
你知道车里有什么贵重物品吗
Was there anything of value you know was inside?
不
No.
据我所知没有
Not that I know of.
你们就找到这些
This is all you found?
不
No.
还有这个
There was this.
他去了哪
Where did he go?
作品都去哪了
Where's the art?
你为什么一开始要相信他
Why would you trust him in the first place?
我没告诉他箱子里是什么
I didn't tell him what was in the crates.
他只需要把箱子运到兰卡斯特的一个库房
All he had to do was deliver them to a warehouse in Lancaster.
这事情要出岔子了  跟你明说
This shit goes sideways, and I'm telling you straight up,
我会说这都是你的注意  跟我没关系
I will say this was all your idea. I had nothing to do with it.
这是布莱森的手机  显然我没接电话
This is Bryson's phone. obviously, I didn't pick up.
布莱森  是我
Bryson, it's me.
你他妈在哪
Where the fuck are you?
你要跟我来硬的  自己卷钱跑吗
You trying to strong-arm me, cash in on your own? What?
别他妈搞我  布莱森  回我电话
Don't fuck with me, Bryson. Call me.
我来的时机正好
I came at the right time.
不不  现在不是时候
- - No, no. Not now.
我有很多事做
I have a lot to do.
又不是要搞三个小时
Wha... It's not for three hours.
我准备就要花这么久
It'll take me that long to get ready.
就是个募捐活动
It's just a fundraiser.
要拍照的
There's going to be pictures.
我们第一次一起出席  这对我很重要
Our first time out. This is super important to me.
我想看上去光鲜动人
I wanna look good.
我找到条不错的裙子
I found a sick dress.
这个沙发对于天花板的高度来说太小了
This sofa's completely too small for the ceiling height.
看上去孤零零的
It swims in here.
我在给那本书归档画作
So, I've been cataloging paintings for the book.
但有些不对劲
Something doesn't add up.
怎么了
What's that?
里面几乎没有研究图和草图  看上去遗失了
There's almost no studies or sketches. They seem to be missing.
不同时期之间也有巨大的空隙
As well as large gaps from different periods of his work.
他给画作标了日期
He dated them, you know.
不  我找到的都在那了
No, everything I found is there.
相信我  如果还有我一定会知道的
Trust me, I'd know.
冰箱里有高档香槟酒
I've got some great champagne in the fridge.
我们一边准备一边喝吧
Open it while we get ready.
敦顿画廊
走的时候记得来看看
Stop by before you leave.
三点钟方向  招聘档案管理员的面试
Your three o'clock is here. Interview for the archivist opening.
你年纪太小了
You're too young.
我22岁了
I'm twenty-two.
这个职位需要多年的工作经验
The position requires someone with years of experience.
等你40岁了再来吧
Stop back when you're forty, eh?
这就完了
That's it?
没错
That is it.
你在洛多拉那里干过
You worked for Rhodora?
就几周时间
Just for a few weeks.
所以我不受非竞争条款的限制
So, the non-compete clause doesn't apply.
-她把你开除了  -我当时在茶歇
- She fired you? - I was on a break.
有个男的闯进来和她说了几句话
A man walked in and talked to her,
她就揪着这事不放了
and she never let it go.
你也参加了迪斯的开幕画展吗
You were there for the Dease opening?
-乱成了一锅粥  -你知道她赚了多少吗
- It was a zoo. - You know how much she generated?
-我看到了那笔数目  -买家名单呢
- I saw the numbers. - The buyers list?
每个都知道
Every name.
你的客户买了两幅
Your client bought two.
挺机智
Very resourceful.
干这行就必须机智
I've learned that you have to be.
洛多拉锁住了一份迪斯的档案
Rhodora had, um, a file on Dease that she kept locked away.
有天我找到了钥匙...
One day I found the key and...
内容非常吸引人
it was a very interesting read.
我好像确实有个职位空缺
You know what? I might have an opening.
进办公室跟我说说你还听到了些什么
Come back to my office and tell me what else you heard.
我还真想念这里呢
I do miss it here.
同事情谊  目的纯粹
The camaraderie, the purity of purpose,
周二的烘肉卷
the Tuesday meatloaf,
还有可以俯瞰沥青坑的咖啡厅
the cafe overlooking the tar pits.
说回正事  维特利尔·迪斯
Well, on to Vetril Dease.
在宇宙联邦里
In the united federation of the universe,
现在应该没有比他更火的画家了
I doubt there is a hotter artist at the moment.
你知道吗  自画展开幕以来
Do you know, since the exhibit opening,
他都上了推特热门
he's actually trending on twitter.
我们对展出他的画作很感兴趣
We're interested in showing him.
你能提供多少幅
How many pieces are we talking about?
我能提供我客户买的两幅
I can supply two owned by my client.
另外还能从迷雾画廊租借十幅
And another ten on loan from the Haze Gallery.
把尺寸和图片发到群里来
Send dimensions and JPEGs for the group,
我们下个季度开展
and we'll aim for a spot next season.
我想马上就展出
I want them exhibited ASAP.
在主展厅里建个新侧厅  还要做活动推广
Main hall, new wing. Event marketing.
这都是要走流程的  格雷琴
You know we have a process, Gretchen.
我给前雇主想了个绝妙的点子
I had a glorious concept to support my former employer,
给所谓的顶尖洛杉矶当代艺术博物馆
and supposed premier contemporary art museum of Los Angeles,
率先展览迪斯的机会
with a first showing of a Dease!
我们很谢谢你的好意
We appreciate the significance,
但是确实位置不够
but there is the issue of space.
那就把班尼欧的「马阴茎」
Well, move Banyo's Horse Penis
或者「镶宝石阴道」撤掉
or the Jeweled Vagina.
把这两个合体我也管不着
Put one inside the other for all I care.
我的客户遇到了税务问题
There is a tax issue,
他想立刻展出他收藏的迪斯画作
and my client wants his Dease exhibited immediately.
为了回报我这个慷慨提议
Now, in return for my very generous offer,
明金斯的「球体」也要一同展出
I also want Minkins' Sphere to be shown.
拜托  格雷琴  我们这里不是地毯集市
Oh, come on, Gretchen, this isn't a rug bazaar.
这是个能得到答案的方程式
No, it's an equation with a solution at the end.
你们要是还不明白的话
And if you can't grasp that,
我可以肯定  会有其他博物馆争着要的
there are other museums, I assure you, that will.
亲亲
Kisses.
萨特勒退伍军人医院百年纪念
抱歉
Sorry.
我没看到你
I didn't see you there.
我叫莫弗·范德瓦尔特
I'm Morf Vandewalt.
我是来调查研究维特利尔·迪斯的
I'm here researching Vetril Dease.
-我在写一本关于他的书  -做什么
- I'm... writing a book about him. - What for?
他现在是炙手可热的画家
He's... He's become a prominent artist
但是非主流派别
in... in the outsider school.
你和他共事过吗
Did... Did you work with him?
18年
Eighteen years.
您能不能当帮我个大忙
Well, it would be extremely helpful
我们约个时间深入聊聊他
if we could arrange a time to talk in depth.
我有很多问题想问
You see, I have so many questions,
但是知道他的人少之又少
and there's so few people who knew him.
你本可以去找那个退伍老兵聊的
There was a vet you could've talked to.
他有几枚勋章  还是个大嘴巴
He had a few medals and a loud mouth.
很喜欢嘲讽人  尤其是迪斯
Liked to ride people, particularly Dease.
但他最后死在了田里
He wound up dead in a field.
双手被绑着
Hands tied.
到现在都没查出凶手
Never found who did it.
你的意思是这是迪斯干的
So, you're saying it was Dease?
-我操  -天哪
- Damn it! - Oh! Jesus.
我是要你别再管他的事了
I'm saying you left him the fuck alone.
我没什么好说的了
Look, I have nothing more to say.
你去跟另外那个家伙也说一声
And you can tell that other damn fella that, too.
谁
Who?
昨天来的那个
The one who came by here yesterday.
我不知道是谁
I don't know who that would be.
给
Here.
雷·拉斯金斯皮尔
私家侦探  洛城警局退休警官
我们已经证实迪斯曾被监禁20年
Well, we've corroborated Dease's twenty-year incarceration,
调查内容包括庭审文件  警方记录
using court documents, police records,
还有他的工作经历
and work history.
迪斯在18岁那年离开了圣殿骑士孤儿院
Dease left the Good Templars Orphanage at 18.
应征参军了两年
He was drafted. Served two years in the army.
服完兵役后
And when he got out,
他遭遇了精神崩溃
he suffered some sort of a breakdown.
在那个时候
At that point,
他找到了虐待他的父亲并将其杀害
he tracked down his abusive father and murdered him.
但他不是就地杀害的
He didn't kill him right away, tho.
而是拖了好几天
He dragged it out for days,
折磨他  最后把他活活烧死
torturing him, then burning him alive.
迪斯在关押精神病罪犯的医院里
Dease spent two decades in a psychiatric hospital
过了二十年
for the criminally insane.
医院会用罪犯做医学实验
The facility used inmates for medical experiments.
注射  电击
Injections, shocks.
天知道还有什么行径
God knows what else.
他们就是活体实验品
They were human guinea pigs.
迪斯在法院关闭医院之后被释放了
Dease got released when the courts closed it.
从那时起他就来到了洛杉矶
From there he goes to LA
在老兵之家找了个工作  过着隐居生活
and got a job at the veterans home and lived off the grid.
没有银行账户  汽车和驾照
No bank account, car, license.
连个可用的照片都没有
Couldn't even find a usable photo.
你确定这些都经过证实了吗
And you verified all this? You're sure?
都核查过了
It all checked out.
我说的都是事实
Those are the facts.
好吧  我明天就发布这些消息
All right, I'm gonna release this tomorrow.
到时候你得向新闻媒体发言
I'm gonna need you to speak to the press,
证明你的资质
attesting to your credentials,
还有文件内容的真实性
the authenticity of what's in the file, and...
以及你的这些发现
and the atrocious and disturbing nature
是多么的穷凶极恶  令人不安之类的
of what you found, et cetera, et cetera.
我以为这些信息会让他的作品升值
I thought this kind of stuff would raise the value of his work.
那不是
Oh, no, no.
这是另一回事了
This is another level.
-晚安  -晚安
- Have a good night. - Nighty-night.
拉斯金斯皮尔和合伙人
我是莫弗  请留言
You've reached Morf. Leave a message.
你好啊  莫弗  我是乔恩
Howzit, Morf? It's Jon.
请尽快回电
Give me a call back as soon as you can.
我想跟你聊聊迪斯的事
I have something regarding Dease.
你应该会很感兴趣
I think might interest you greatly.
有人吗
Hello?
搞什么
What the hell?
乔恩
Jon?
我们一时半会儿是别想走了
Oh, we are just stuck in here, aren't we?
这俗气的管风琴音乐是怎么回事
What is with that cheesy organ music?
还有那副棺材  是什么颜色
And that casket. What color is that?
雾橙色  他打折买的吗
Smog orange? Did he buy it on sale?
小声点说
Not so loud.
说真的  想想他要永远都待在那里面
Seriously, imagine having to spend an eternity in that.
天啊  你就没有看得顺眼的东西
Jesus. Nothing is ever good enough for you.
这是我的工作  我得讲究
Well, it's my job. I'm selective.
你这话又是什么意思
What are you even saying?
抛掉我的品味和标准
Toss out taste and standards?
只能低声说出真相吗
Whisper the truth?
那样的世界该有多悲惨
What a tragic world that would be.
我是约瑟芬娜
I'm Josephina.
我是洛多拉的同事  画廊合伙人
I work with Rhodora. I'm a partner at the gallery.
-你好  我叫达米什  -我当然知道
- Oh, yeah. Damrish. -O h, of course.
-我特别喜欢你的作品  -谢谢
- I am just such a huge fan your work. - Thank you.
迪斯的收藏是我负责的
I do the Dease collection.
你的审美超凡脱俗
It's otherworldly.
-谢谢  -因为你的评论让"流浪侠"滞销了
- Thank you. - Your review of Hoboman killed the sale.
它没有受人观赏  而是在仓库里落灰
Instead of being seen, it's gathering dust at a storage facility.
我又不是你的代言人
I am not your mouthpiece.
天啊
God.
我们什么事都会争
We competed for everything,
但我真的很厌恶因为这种事来这里
but I absolutely despise being here for this.
他是遇到了什么事才会做出这种举动
I mean, what was he facing, to do something like that?
我们上次谈话  他还是不改肤浅的老样子
He was his usual shallow self the last time we spoke.
我又开始喝酒了
Started drinking again.
快乐时光又回来了啊
Ooh, happy days.
这个位置是留给亲友的
Um, this here is for family and friends only.
乔恩是在我的画廊做起的
Well, Jon started at my gallery, so...
不然我要坐哪里
I mean, where the hell else would I sit?
女士们先生们  我们要开始了
Ladies and gentleman, if we may begin.
-你是吃了伟哥吗  -我快射了
- Did you take a Viagra or something? - I'm almost there.
等下  换后入
No. I'm going on my back.
-别  -我这个姿势不行
- No. - I can't stay like this.
睁眼
Open your eyes.
我在你下面
I'm down here.
我去
Oh, God damn it.
有点不对劲
Something's wrong.
我们遇到了操蛋问题  说真的
We've got a fucking problem. Literally.
我看到有东西...
I'm seeing things, um...
有东西在动
Things moving.
真的  我被吓着了
Seriously, I'm really scared.
之前你的热情让我欲火焚身
I was turned on by your passion,
你睿智的头脑也是
from listening to your intelligent mind,
但你现在却变成了这副鬼样子
and now you've turned into I don't know what.
你的评论也掉价了
Your reviews have fallen off,
而且你还是忘不掉艾德  承认吧
and you still have feelings for Ed, admit it.
我心里已经没有艾德了
I do not have feelings for Ed.
格雷琴碰到了他
Gretchen ran into him,
他说你们还在商量着要继续走下去
and he said that you two were talking and working it out.
那艾德就是个大骗子
Well, Ed is a big liar,
格雷琴是个婊子
and Gretchen is a bitch!
我看了你手机  你打了六通电话
I checked your phone. You made six calls.
我们是在沟通他搬出去住的事情
He was moving out, we were coordinating.
还有你说我的评论掉价是什么意思
What do you mean, my reviews have fallen off?
你的眼光
Your eye.
你的角度  倒也说得通
Your edge. Makes sense.
你不知道自己喜欢或者想要什么
You don't know what you like or even want.
那我告诉你我到底喜欢什么
I'll tell you what I did like.
瑞奇·布莱恩的展
Ricky Blane's show.
但你逼我毁了他
But you jammed me to crush him!
别赖我头上
Don't lay that on me.
这又不是你写的第一篇差评  得了吧
Like he was your first bad review. Gimme a break.
我没说我怪你
I'm not saying that I blame you.
我是说我很后悔
I'm saying that I regret it.
我可能是花了太长时间
I think that I've been staring too long
研究迪斯的画作和资料
at all this Dease art and all his material.
我过几天去检查视力  会好起来的
I'm... I'm gonna get my vision checked. This will pass.
听听我睿智的想法
Listen to my intelligent mind.
怎么样
Well?
无感
I'm not pickled.
可能你这只是刚开头  但是...
It's a small step, I suppose, toward something, but
我就实话实说了
let's talk turkey.
你到底在畏惧什么
What are you afraid of?
我们是老相识了
We go way, way back.
我给你看样东西
I wanna share with you a little somethin' somethin'.
"依赖会扼杀创造力
"Dependency murders creativity.
创造力和未知作伴
Creativity plays with the unknown.
没有任何策略能够封闭漫无边际的
No strategies exist that can enclose the endless realm
全新领域
of the new.
唯有相信自己
Only trust in yourself
才能让你抛下恐惧
can carry you past your fears
和已知的世界"
and the already known."
这是波利·安娜在1983年写的
That's Polly Anna, 1983.
我在她过量用药后帮她清理公寓时找到的
I found it clearing out her apartment after she OD'd.
虽然我很早之前就放弃走画家这条路了
I gave up being an artist a long time ago,
但我知道这一行的规则
but I know how this works.
先把艺术世界放到一边吧
Forget about the art world.
你需要逃离这里  这一切  喘口气
You need to get away from here, from all this. Take a break.
你可以住去我的海滨别墅
Use my beach house and stay there
等到你只为自己而活时再回来
until you do something for nobody but yourself.
哪个更清晰  一号
Which one's better? One.
-还是二号  -二号
- Two. - Two.
好  现在呢  一号二号哪个清晰
All right. Two. One. Better, worse, no different?
没区别
No different.
好了
All right. There we go.
好的
All right. Well,
自上次之后你的视力其实有所提升
your acuity has actually improved since your last prescription.
我希望你能找出问题的原因
I was hoping you'd find something to explain what's happening.
那些幻影移动吗
The phantom movements?
我觉得我得了邦纳症候群
I think I have Charles Bonnet syndrome.
幻觉  幻象  移动的物体
Hallucinations, visions, moving objects.
你去谷歌了  我就知道
You've been on the Internet. Yeah.
我觉得不太可能  因为你没有其他症状
It's highly doubtful in the absence of other factors.
但这周我们再安排一次会诊
But let's make another appointment for this week.
我放大了你的瞳孔  所以你得佩戴几小时这个
I dilated your eyes, so you have to wear these for a few hours.
这实在是丑爆了
These are heinous.
该死
Shit.
操
Fuck.
喂  哪位
Yes, who is this?
-是我  -真聪明  你隐藏了自己的号码
- It's me. - Oh, how clever. You blocked your number.
因为你不接我电话
'Cause you won't answer my calls.
鉴于你昨天的那通恶毒留言  你很意外吗
Well, after your vile voice message yesterday, are you surprised?
什么  我
Wha-- I--
你竟然告诉约瑟芬娜我还和艾德在一起
Telling Josephina I am still with Ed?
-所以这是我的错吗  -我们分手了
- Oh! That's my crime? - We broke up.
我只是和他商量搬出去的事
I was coordinating with him moving out.
说实话  我期待你会向我道歉
Honestly, I expected an apology.
艾德很明确地说了不止搬家的事
Ed said precisely there was more to it than that.
我只是个传话人
I merely passed it on.
你真是个天大的笑话
You're a joke!
没有任何信誉可言
You have no credibility in any way!
是吗  既然如此
Oh, really? Well, in that case,
那我猜你的小伙伴约瑟芬娜
I suppose there's no truth whatsoever
围着达米什转悠也不是真的了
in your little friend Josephina sniffing around Damrish,
容我多嘴一句
who, might I add,
他俩正准备比翼双飞驶入夕阳呢
are literally about to drive off into the sunset together.
姬塔
Gita?
我就是
Yes.
-我是莫弗·范德...  -范德瓦尔特
- I'm Morf Vande-- - Vandewalt.
-没错  -当然了  我一直看你写的艺评
- Yes. - Of course. I've read you for years.
幸会
Yes.
新买的墨镜吗
Are those the new Persols?
嗯  没错
Yeah. That's right.
那是弗洛伊德的画作
That's a Freud.
卢西安·弗洛伊德  英国最伟大的当代表现派画家之一
-没错  -我从没见过这幅
- Yes, it is. - I've never seen that one before.
从92年起这幅画就待在箱子中
It's been in a crate since '92.
同时这也是它的归宿
And it's going back in one.
对了  我喜欢你制作的迪斯展览手册
I loved your exhibit brochure on Dease, by the way.
谢谢
Thank you.
正如我在电话里所说  我想把手册扩写为一本书
As I said on the phone, I'm expanding it into a book.
内容肯定绰绰有余
Well, there's enough there for one.
你编目了售前展览的作品
You cataloged the collection presale.
没有编目
Oh, not cataloged.
我的工作重心变成了研究迪斯独特的作画方法
My primary focus became Dease's distinctive methodology.
我花了三周时间研究习俗
I spent three weeks identifying conventions,
工作流程  作品分类
workflow, classifications.
几乎无法区分
It was almost impossible to delineate
作画材料和个人物品
between working materials and personal effects.
说实话  我很高兴完成了
Frankly, I was glad to finish.
我不知道除了我手里的那些作品
Well, I wasn't aware there were any personal effects
还有其他的个人物品
besides the ones in my possession.
不是传统意义上的个人物品
None in a traditional sense.
我是说组织[纸巾]一类的
I mean, as in tissue.
画纸吗
Paper?
也许你该和洛多拉谈谈
Perhaps you should speak with Rhodora.
洛多拉
Rhodora is...
非常支持这本书
backing the book.
不用多说她全力支持我且对我有信心
I have her full support and confidence, of course.
血清那种组织
Tissue as in blood serum.
我猜是画家自己的血清
The artist's, I assume.
他用血清调出了黑红色和阴影
He used it to create the reddish blacks and the shadows.
我们研究的每幅画里都有
It was in every piece we studied.
即使是你  这个要求也太过分了
That is an outrageous request. Even coming from you.
我不懂你们为什么要推迟展出明克斯的作品
I don't get your pushback on a Minkins retrospective here,
不过是在秋季展出他所有的主要作品
in the fall, of all his major works.
我们已经同意展出「球体」
We already agreed to put up Sphere
来换你的十二幅迪斯画作
in exchange for you bringing us twelve Dease.
说真的  格雷琴  这么做既无礼又愚蠢
Seriously, Gretchen, it's rude and dumb.
如果你想把你老板手中的藏品
If you wanted to ram more of your collector's hoard
强塞给我们以增加其价值
down our throats to increase their value,
你应该在决定展出迪斯之前就下手
you should have done so before the Dease deal was locked,
而不是在展览的前一天晚上
not the night before the exhibit's open.
我听说市场部很期望做迪斯作品巡回展
I hear marketing has high hopes of a traveling Dease collection.
他们甚至已经做了个规划
They've even run projections.
所以我相信我的筹码还是很可观的
So, I believe my "Leverage" looking ahead is considerable.
秋季绝对没有档期展出明克斯的作品了
There's absolutely no space in the fall to put on a Minkins show.
明天我要和你们的董事会见面
Well, I'm going to meet with your board tomorrow
建议减少新兴艺术家展览
and suggest a reduction in the emerging artist exhibit.
反正它们也不卖座
They don't sell any tickets anyway.
想得美
Over my dead body.
格雷琴
Gretchen?
官宣材料稿件已经整理好
The hard copy PR material's been sorted,
电子工具盒半夜已发出
and the electronic kits get sent at midnight.
明天早点来
Be here early.
并提前告诉我到场的任何明星或艺术家
And inform me of any celebrities or art stars.
如果可以的话
Um, if it's all right with you,
我想回家休息几小时
I'd like to go home and get a few hours of sleep?
「球体」的灯光调整了吗
Has the lighting been corrected on Sphere?
侧灯  是的  我留了侧灯
Oh, the side lights, yes. I had them leave it lit,
这样你离开时就能看见它了
so you could see it when you leave.
那你回去吧
Then run along.
晚安
Good night.
球体的演变
选择一个洞探索
也许你找不到
但你能找到
救命
Help!
我毛茸茸的动物喜欢被爱抚
救命
Help!
喂
Hello.
不会吧
No.
什么时候
When?
今天早上
This morning.
不知怎么地她被卡在了里面
Somehow she got stuck inside of it.
发生了一些故障  然后我猜大概是
There was some kind of malfunction, and I guess it just, like,
作品把她整个手臂卸了  她因失血过多死亡
completely took her arm off and she bled to death.
太可怕了
It was horrible.
保安以为尸体是艺术品的新装置
Security guards thought it was part of a new installation,
所以他们开门让人们进去参观了
so they just opened up and let people in.
昨晚迪斯展览的弹出窗口宣传大获成功
The Dease pop-up announcement was blasted last night,
所以大家都前去参观
so everyone was heading there.
人们走过她的尸体  仿佛她是展览的一部分
People just walked by like she was part of an exhibit.
然后来了一群学校的孩子
Then a school tour came along.
孩子们以为地上是假血
The kids thought it was fake blood,
于是就开始踩着玩
so they just started stepping in it
并踩得到处都是
and spreading it around and...
如果不是可可要处理迪斯展览的新闻发布
Who knows how long it would have gone on for
谁知道这群小孩会玩到什么时候
until Coco came in to do press for the Dease show,
可可看到了格雷琴后直接就奔溃了
and she saw Gretchen and just lost it.
你还在吗
Are you still there?
洛多拉
Rhodora?
我不明白
I don't understand.
先是布莱森  然后乔恩  现在又是格雷琴
Bryson, then Jon. Now Gretchen.
到底怎么回事
What the fuck is going on?
我不知道
I don't know.
我们昨晚才见过她
I mean, we just saw her last night.
他们关闭了博物馆的那栋楼  但是
They closed that wing of the museum, but...
我听说迪斯的展览人满为患
I hear the Dease exhibit is mobbed.
走开
Hey. Go.
我们在朋友圈和照片墙火爆了  上了热搜榜
We're spiking on Moments and Instagram. It's a major hit.
洛多拉  你还在吗
Rhodora, are you still there?
你听见我刚说的了吗
Did you hear what I just said?
听见了
Yeah.
迪斯的展览风生水起
The Dease exhibit is booming.
有人敲门  我得挂了
There's someone at my door. I gotta go.
你有没有...
Did you...
听说格雷琴的事
hear about Gretchen?
你听说了吗
Did you?
我的天
Oh, Jesus.
-你能相信吗  -你得走了
- Can you believe it? - You have to leave.
你不能就这样  这样进来
You just can't, well, just walk in like this!
我现在不想一个人待着
Well, I need to be with someone right now.
我觉得你也是
I'd think you would, too.
怎么回事
What's going on?
你在逗我玩吗
Are you kidding me?
我们没在约会  之前我就说明白了
We're not together. I was clear.
你说"暂时分开"
You said, "A break."
我对你作品的景仰之情
The admiration I had for your work
已经完全消失殆尽
has completely evaporated!
老兄  我可没打算夺你所爱  好吗
Hey, man, I wasn't trying to jump your train, okay?
她说你俩玩完了
She said you two were done.
是吗  是吗
Are we? Are we?
说我们俩之前没有真情实感
Say we don't share something real.
我从没有特别着迷你
I was never particularly obsessed.
我们昨天就盼着您来了
We expected you yesterday.
我们闭展半日  期待着您的大驾光临
We closed the exhibit for half a day in anticipation, actually.
我以为艺术网站把时间说的很清楚
I thought Artweb were clear on the timing.
我知道  抱歉  是我的错
I know, I'm sorry. It's my fault.
我知道这是首展
I know it's pre-debut.
只是我最近有些私事要处理
Just been experiencing some personal matters.
然后  你懂的  今早格雷琴的惨剧
Then, of course, Gretchen this morning.
-如果现在不是时候...  -不  没关系
- If this isn't a good time... - No, it's fine.
我早该来了
It's overdue.
我今天就把评论写好并发出
I'll write my review and file it today.
莉莉斯·范兰迪根用她的革新性
Lillith Vanlandingham is storming the world
声音展览冲击着世界的耳膜
with her revolutionary sound exhibits.
去年她获得了白南准艺术中心奖
She won the Nam June Paik Award last year.
她最新的作品叫做「须鲸」
Her latest piece is called Mysticete.
根据约定
As discussed,
我们安排让您单独体验展览
we have arranged for you to experience the exhibit alone.
瞧瞧他站在那
Look at him standing there.
他只接受自己懂得的艺术
He only embraces what he knows.
毫无疑问是现代艺术历史上最糟糕的展览之一
Undoubtedly one of the worst exhibits of contemporary art history.
一块又一块
Piece for piece,
这是自泰坦尼克号以来浪费钢铁最严重的一次了
it's the biggest waste of steel since the Titanic.
这种令人痛苦的展览就该被连根铲除
This painful exhibit should be bulldozed.
去掉天花乱坠的炒作  他新作就是场无聊盛宴
Remove the spotlight of hype and his latest work is a snoozefest.
不是开玩笑  米纳蒂女士  我在和你说话
Seriously, Ms. Minati, I am talking to you.
似乎你周围没有人告诉你  停下吧
It seems you have no one around you to say this. Stop it.
放弃吧
Shut up the shed.
这场展览毫无可取之处
There are no redeeming qualities to the show.
只有难堪  展览唯一的亮点
Nothing but embarrassed-- The best thing about the show
就是供应了法国桃红葡萄酒
is the French rosé being offered.
这幅作品丑陋得无法直视  还会引起轻微反胃
It's an ugly piece to look at, and faintly nauseating.
从无知愚蠢升级到...
It's gone from innocent and stupid...
你这句话我会记恨一辈子
I'll hate you forever for saying that!
-毫不上心地隐藏  -卑鄙  骗子
- Lazily concealed. - Vile. Deceitful!
骗子
Deceitful!
莫弗
Morf!
评论也该被评价
Judgment should be judged.
这是一场巨大的失败
It is a monumental failure.
莫弗
Morf!
瑞奇·布莱恩是典型的
Ricky Blane is the classic case
装腔作势引领潮流的冒牌货
of presenting a poser as cutting edge.
抱歉耽搁了  刚才电脑死机了
Sorry for the delay. Our computer crashed.
我们  我们现在就开始
We're-- We'll start it now.
那我刚才听到的是什么
What did I just hear?
什么也没放  这是一间隔音房
Nothing. This is a soundproof room.
声...
Voi...
各种声音
Voices.
我不知道
I've no idea.
「须鲸」是一场马里亚纳海沟下
Mysticete is a symphony of whale intonation
两万英尺处鲸鱼抑扬顿挫声调相互交融的交响乐
recorded 20,000 feet under the sea in the Mariana Trench.
您准备好了吗
You are up for this?
我看见了一些东西
I am seeing things.
听到了不存在的声音
I'm hearing things.
无法解释的事情
Unexplainable things.
不可能发生的事情
Impossible things.
作为现世主义的拥护者
And this is hard to admit
和坚定鄙夷幼稚迷信的我来说
as an adherent of the here and now
承认这一点很困难
and a denier of childish belief.
但有离奇至极的事情正在发生
But something truly goddamn strange is going on!
布莱森到底怎么了
What happened to Bryson?
根据警方调查  他出了车祸
According to the police, he had an accident
然后神志恍惚走入了沙漠
and he wandered into the desert.
我和警察谈过
I spoke to the police.
他们有布莱森
They have video surveillance
失踪当晚的监控录像
of the night that Bryson went missing.
他的卡车装着满满几箱艺术品
He was loading crates of art into his truck.
好吧
Okay.
那些箱子里是什么
What was in those crates?
与这些事又有什么关系
And all this relates how?
迪斯
Dease!
他扭曲的精神状态
His altered mental state,
受尽折磨的灵魂  月亮的阴晴圆缺
tortured soul, phases of the goddamn moon!
我不知道是如何发生的
I don't know how!
但这些死亡
These deaths.
失踪
The disappearance.
现在正发生的一切
Everything that is now happening,
都跟他的作品有关
it's all connected to his art.
他的画里有邪灵
Imbued with some spirit...
或是根据某种致命的原型创作
cr... created out of some vital ideal.
这有点巴洛克  你不觉得吗
It's a bit Baroque, don't you think?
-我是来警告你的  -好吧
- I came here to warn you. - Okay.
我知道这几周很混乱难熬
You know what? It's been a fucked-up few weeks!
但你听听自己说的疯话
But listen to yourself!
我做调查时找大楼业主聊过
I spoke to the building owners during research.
他们听说
They were surprised
迪斯的作品在出售  都很惊讶
to hear Dease's art was being sold.
显然
Apparently,
他留下了很明确的遗言  要把作品全销毁
he left explicit instructions that it all be destroyed.
-你想说什么  -别再卖迪斯的作品了
- What are you saying? - Stop selling Dease!
他的藏品能卖八位数
It's an eight-figure collection...
就因为什么幽灵  你想让我停止出售吗
...and you want me to stop selling over some spirit?
我在写一篇与这有关的文章
I am writing an article about this.
关于迪斯  他的过去  他的方法论
About Dease, his past, his methods,
所发生的所有事
everything that has gone down.
-你会毁了自己的事业  -把作品处理掉
- Well, you'll kill your career. - Get rid of it.
都装进盒子里扔掉
Box it all, all of it away.
我就准备这么做
That's what I'm doing.
所有艺术都是危险的  莫弗
All art is dangerous, Morf.
首次展出后就有很多人竞相出价
Oh, it's just been a feeding frenzy since the debut.
但经过重新衡量  我们发现
What's changed is we ran new metrics and realized that
对供货的数量过于谨慎了
we've been overly precious with supply.
我给你发了六张迪斯作品的图片
I sent you six Dease JPEGs,
都可以立即以报价购买
all available for immediate purchase at the quoted price
这些作品一定会大幅升值
and destined for significant appreciation.
全都买下吗  太好了
All of them. Well, that's swell.
我把相关文件发给你
I'll send the papers.
好的
Okay. Yeah.
我们在巴塞尔见
I'll see you in Basel.
怎么回事
What's going on?
迪斯的首期销售不是结束了吗  为什么继续出售
We closed the first phase on Dease. Why are we selling more?
莫弗执意要写一篇文章
Morf is hell-bent on writing a story.
他觉得布莱森的失踪
He's connecting Bryson's disappearance
乔恩和格雷琴的死  都与迪斯的作品有关
and Jon and Gretchen's deaths to the Dease art.
他认为那些作品以某种方式引出了某种...
He believes they're somehow channeling some sort of...
邪灵
spirit.
Spirit?
什么邪灵
What kind of spirit?
我对这种事又不了解
I don't know the varieties.
就算他写疯狂的故事又怎样  没人在乎
So he writes some batshit story. Who cares?
我们不是在卖耐用品  而是传播概念
We don't sell durable goods, we peddle perception.
一戳即破
Thin as a bubble.
打给你的买家们
Call your buyers,?
在莫弗发表文章前  尽量多卖出几幅迪斯
sell as much Dease as you can before he posts something.
-下一个是谁  -罗克西在一线
- Who's next? - You have Roxy on one.
亲爱的
Hey, babe.
你之前说想买几幅有收藏价值的迪斯
Checking back on you wanting some museum-quality Dease.
未接来电
约瑟芬娜
宝贝  沙发是生丝的  脚放下来
Baby, that's raw silk. Your shoes.
把瓶盖打开
Pop this.
你的手劲真大
You've got strong hands.
你有没有认真看过这幅画
You ever look at this painting?
你有发现过异常吗
You ever notice anything about this painting?
只要一直盯着看  画就会动
You look at it long enough and it moves.
这幅画是活的
It's alive.
-我刚把这幅画卖了  -什么  我本来也想买
- I've just sold it. - What? I would have bought it.
你又买不起
You couldn't afford it.
我们不想要的  相信我  我这是在帮你
We don't want it. Trust me, I'm doing you a favor.
我得赶去特拉克逊大道
I gotta get down to Traction Avenue.
-我们不是今晚打算在家里度过吗  -本来是
- I thought we were spending the night in. - Yeah.
但刚发生了些事  我今晚必须去处理
Something just came up, and I gotta take care of it tonight.
你要放我鸽子
You're blowing me off.
我想要你一起来
I want you to come.
你为什么一直打给我
Why do you keep calling me?
你还问为什么
Why?
我们分手
We break up,
你就写一篇文章来彻底毁掉我的生计
and you write an article to completely destroy my livelihood.
我这么做不是为了报复你
I am not doing this to get back at you.
是因为迪斯的作品
It's Dease's art.
通过他作品获利的人都有危险
I think any of us who profited from it are in danger.
所以你就昭告天下吗
So, you just blasted it out there?
老天  我现在正在读你的文章
Jesus Christ. I am reading it right now.
你知不知道自己彻底疯了
Are you aware that you've completely lost your mind?
直到失去后  我们才意识到朋友有多重要
We don't realize the value of friends until they're gone.
我仍视你为朋友  约瑟芬娜
I still consider you a friend, Josephina.
你去死吧  把我号码删了
Go fuck yourself and lose my number!
那好吧  再见
Well, fine, then. Bye.
喂
Hello?
我是莫弗
It's Morf.
我计划有变
A timetable is moved up.
我要存放一些画作  但我马上要离开
I'm storing some art and I'm leaving immediately.
我不在的期间  需要一个兼职助手帮我
I need an assistant part-time here while I'm gone.
-我有空  -今晚就开工可以吗
- Well, I'm available. - Yeah. Can you start tonight?
应该可以  没问题
I guess so. Sure.
我要把我家和储存室的钥匙给你
I need to give you the keys to my house and my storage space.
穆赫兰大道上有个观景台  刚过卡汉加路口
There's an overlook on Mulholland, right off Cahuenga.
-我知道在哪里  -很好  我在那里等你
- I know the one. - Good. I'll meet you there.
范德瓦尔特先生  你好
Mr. Vandewalt. Hi.
那篇文章我发了  可可
I posted it, Coco.
文章发出去之后  我...
And with this article,?I'm... I'm...
我等于往自己身上浇汽油  点燃火柴
I'm pouring gas on myself. I'm lighting a match.
但我别无选择
I don't have a choice.
我现在知道了
It has been revealed to me
有某种更强大的力量
that there is some sort of larger power...
某种物质  存在于我们的事业
some entity invested in our endeavor.
怎么存在
Invested how?
通过
In...
违反
the violation
不可违反的规则
of inviolate rules.
我是不是疯了
Have I gone mad?
我不认为
Not to me.
我可是发现了两具尸体
I found both bodies.
我睡觉都不敢关灯
I'm sleeping with my lights on.
除此以外  如果我再不找到稳定工作
On top of which, if I don't land a steady job soon,
我就得回密歇根老家了
I'm gonna have to go back to Michigan.
有件事我必须告诉你
I have to tell you something.
什么事
What?
我之前不是担任过洛多拉的私人助理吗
I was Rhodora's personal assistant, right?
我看过她的支票  我帮她转接电话
I saw her checks, I rolled calls with her.
她有时好像忘记我也在线上
I think she sometimes forgot when I was on them.
告诉我
Tell me.
你的前男友  艾德
Your ex-boyfriend, Ed, um...
他之前为她工作
he worked for her.
他帮她健身  他是私教
He worked her out. He's a personal trainer.
不
No.
不  我是指
No, I mean...
洛多拉雇用艾德  让他提前把你的评论告诉她
Rhodora paid Ed to give her advance word on your reviews.
就是  他会在你发表评论前把你喜欢的作品告诉她
Like, okay... He would tell her what you liked before you posted,
然后她就买下那些作品
and then she'd make buys.
我没被你炒鱿鱼吧
Do I still have the job?
这是我的储存室的钥匙
Here are the keys to my storage space.
你把里面所有作品做好详细登记
I need everything itemized that's there.
好的
Okay.
我的车停在外面安全吗
Is my car safe out there?
我他妈鬼知道
How the fuck should I know?
你去哪了
Where did you go?
这是本  他代理我以前的系列作品
This is Ben. He runs my old artist collective.
很好  我们可以走了吗
Lovely. Can we go now?
我要留下来
I'm staying.
但我不太喜欢这里
But I don't really like this place.
我是指更长期的打算
Yeah, I'm talking longer timeline.
我打算离开洛多拉和她的画廊
I'm leaving Rhodora, her gallery.
你不能离开
No, you're not.
我没法待在那
I can't be there.
我们准备办一场盛大的展览  你嗑嗨了  走吧
We have a significant show planned. You're high. Come on.
我是认真的
I'm serious.
你马上就要获得重大突破
You're about to break big.
我们会让你名扬世界
We're taking you global.
你愿意放弃这些吗  为了什么
You'd give that up? For what?
在可悲的车库里叫卖涂鸦壁画吗
Some sad garage space peddling graffiti murals?
老天  如果没人看到  艺术还有什么意义
Jesus! What's the point of art if nobody sees it?
操
Fuck!
有辆车挡住了我的车  请过来拖走它
Yeah, there's a car blocking my car. I want it towed.
我不知道
I don't know.
稍等
Hang on.
第七街2057号
Oh, 2057 Seventh Street.
我在这等着
I'm waiting.
有人吗
Hello?
潘兴  1969
泰特
汤伯利  1983
我只是进来等拖车
I'm just waiting for a tow truck.
迪斯  2002
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.
约瑟芬娜  来电
喂
Hello?
达米什要走
Damrish is leaving.
他刚才在廉价酒吧跟他以前的代理人见面
He met his old exhibitor in a dive bar
他说要回去  结束了
and told me he's going back. It's over.
对他来说是好事
Good for him.
这话是什么意思  你在说什么
What do you mean, good for him? What are you talking about?
约瑟芬娜
Josephina, are you aware
你知道迪斯要求把自己作品全部销毁吗
that Dease asked that all his art be destroyed?
销毁了难道就会有什么不同吗
Would it have changed anything?
我要是知道了  当初会销毁吗
Would I have destroyed them?
不会
No.
他是艺术大师
He was a master.
天呐  稍等  约瑟芬娜
Oh, Jesus. Hold on, Josephina.
斯黛拉
Stella.
斯黛拉  斯黛拉
Stella. Stella.
斯黛拉  该死
Stella. God damn it.
你感受过被忽视吗
Have you ever felt invisible?
我曾经建过铁路
Once, I built a railroad.
洛多拉
Rhodora?
过来  斯黛拉  过来
Come on, Stella. Come on. Come on.
斯黛拉  过来
Stella, come.
来  乖猫咪  乖猫咪
Come on, good girl. Good girl.
别跑  斯黛拉  该死
Come on, Stella! Damn it!
斯黛拉
Stella!
洛多拉
Rhodora?
天呐
Oh, my God.
天呐  天呐
Oh, my... Oh my...
不  不  我不懂
No, no! No! I understand!
我不懂
I understand!
我救不了你
I can't save you.
老天  真不敢相信刚才发生的事
Jesus Christ, I can't believe what just happened.
洛多拉  通话中
约瑟芬娜  喂
Josephina? Hello?
哪里...
Where...
我操
Oh, fuck me!
迷雾  来电
什么
What?
怎么会
How?
储物仓库
A storage facility?
他们认为发生了什么
Well, what do they think happened?
不  我不回画廊了
No. I'm not coming in.
我得挂了
I gotta go.
快接电话
Pick up the phone.
呼叫  约瑟芬娜
找到车了
Yeah, we got it.
没看见车主
No sign of the owner.
我们准备把车拖回总部
We're taking it to Central.
好
Yeah.
都搬完了
That's all of it.
所有都搬完了吗
Everything?
每张图  每幅画  每张明信片
Every image, every drawing, every postcard,
每件艺术品都搬完了
every piece of art?
-说出来  -都搬空了
- Say it. - It's completely empty.
一共47件  我们都搬走了
Forty-seven pieces. We removed everything.
谢谢你
Thank you.
-去洛杉矶机场  五号航站楼  -好的
- LAX. Terminal five. - Okay.
天鹅绒圆锯
-真好看  是啊
- That's lovely. - Yeah.
多少钱
How much?
五美元好了
I don't know. Five dollars.
好
Yeah.
谢谢你
Thank you.
给
Here you go.
-谢谢  -保重
- Thanks. - Take care.
迷雾画廊